SAI CHANDRA REDDY MANDADAPU

Charlotte, NC| (857) 328-6387 | msaichandrareddy16@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Tableau

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with 4+ years of experience in building ETL pipelines, data models, statistical modeling, dashboards to drive operational and strategic decisions across marketing analytics, retail and supply chain through SQL, GA4, Python, Excel, Power BI, and BigQuery.

SKILLS

Programming Languages : Python, SQL, PL/SQL, R

Database Management Libraries/ Frameworks

: BigQuery, Snowflake, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MongoDB : Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Polars, Statsmodels, Scikit-Learn, Plotly

Tools/Technologies

: Power BI, Tableau, Looker, Microsoft Excel, Google Sheets, Oracle ERP Systems (NetSuite, Fusion), CEM

Systems(Eleads), Databricks, dbt, Git, GitHub, Airflow

BI Skills

: ETL Processing, Data Management, Data Modeling, Data Warehousing, Data Visualization, Reporting, Data Analysis

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst | Mills Automotive Group

November 2024 – Present

- Automated GA4, CRM, and inventory data integration using BigQuery SQL pipelines to identify stocking and lead conversion inefficiencies, streamlining reporting workflows by 60% across 40+ dealerships.
- Built funnel performance dashboards in Looker Studio and Google Sheets, enabling marketing teams to track and identify opportunities in CTR, CPC, CTAs, form submissions — leading to a 6% lift in quality leads.
- Conducted A/B testing, attribution analysis on digital campaigns to optimize marketing ads spent across channels like paid search, shopping ads, OTTs, social media — increasing lead conversion rates to sales from 4.5% to 7.8%.
- Performed statistical analysis on inventory data to identify significant factors influencing faster vehicle sales, improving the turn rate by 14% and reducing the average days on lot by 12%.

Business Intelligence Developer | General Motors

March 2024 - August 2024

- Transformed SAP ERP data in Snowflake by standardizing columns and creating staging, fact, and dimension tables, enabling reliable reporting for material waste analysis for each supplier.
- Designed star schema data modeling in Power BI, created calculated columns and measures using DAX formulas, improved 60% automated tracking of production waste and supplier material usage.
- Improved procurement efficiency from 78% to 81% by identifying high-waste supplier materials through optimized resource allocation.

Technical Business Analyst Co-op | State Street

July 2022 – December 2022

- Enhanced SQL Server stored procedures using T-SQL to improve financial reporting validation logic, reducing downstream reporting discrepancies by 20%.
- Revamped Power BI dashboards connected to JIRA Cloud by redesigning data models, cleaning Power Query tables, and implementing Row-Level Security (RLS), improving KPI accuracy and cutting reporting inconsistencies by 40%.
- Automated monthly JIRA dashboard creation using Python and REST APIs, reducing setup time from 4 hours to under 20 seconds (~99.9% faster) and streamlining sprint tracking for 5+ projects.

Business Intelligence Analyst | Apps Associates

August 2019 - August 2021

- Developed SQL ETL pipelines to extract data from Oracle ERP systems into data warehouse, enabling downstream analysis for retail, ecommerce and supply chain reporting availability for business stakeholders by 30%.
- Built Oracle BI Publisher reports integrated with PL/SQL triggers to automate tracking of EDI order details end to end, reducing manual reporting effort by 20%, accelerating warehouse operations reporting at each stage.
- Performed root cause analysis in Oracle ERP Forms within the O2C order line workflow, resolving planning issues and eliminating 15 hours/week of manual work in order shipping process.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Data Analytics | Northeastern University, Boston, MA Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science | MLR Institute of Technology, India September 2021 – December 2023 August 2015 – May 2019